<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas according to the directions of a late ordinance made amongst other things, for reforming the great defects in streets and pavements, scavengers have been lately chosen within the several parishes of your ward and accordingly sworn to execute that office ...</title>
            <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1654</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09429</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2883GA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R179977</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61297078</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 61297078</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180615</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09429)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180615)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2837:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas according to the directions of a late ordinance made amongst other things, for reforming the great defects in streets and pavements, scavengers have been lately chosen within the several parishes of your ward and accordingly sworn to execute that office ...</title>
                  <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Vyner, Thomas, Sir, 1588-1665.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by James Flesher,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1654]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: city of London coat of arms.</note>
                  <note>Form letter.</note>
                  <note>At end: "Dated the eighth and twentieth day of June 1654."</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Roads --  England --  Maintenance and repair --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Road construction --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:180615:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure>By the Mayor.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <hi>To the Alderman of the Ward of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                        <desc> _____ </desc>
                     </gap> 
                  </hi>
               </salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas according to the directions of a late Ordinance made, amongſt other things, for reforming the great defects in ſtreets and pavements, Scavengers have been lately choſen within the ſeveral Pariſhes of your Ward, and accordingly ſworn to execute that office: To the end there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that the ſaid ſeverall Scavingers within your Ward may diligently apply themſelves to the execution of their office, and that none may pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend ignorance of their duty; Theſe are to deſire you that you cauſe ſpeedy notice to be given by ſending of copies of this Precept to the ſeverall Scavengers of the Pariſhes within your Ward, that they forthwith under the penalties mentioned in the ſaid Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance ſpeedily take an exact view of all the ſtreets and lanes within their reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Pariſhes, and thereupon conſider what defects are within their reſpective Pariſhes by defective Pavements, or by the Channels and Water-courſes not having a good current, and what nuſances are committed by ſuffering Layſtals, heaps of dirt and filth to lie in any Streets or Allies, and whether the ſaid Miſchiefs are occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned by the neglect of any particular perſons, and by them proper to be remedied, or whether the ſame abuſes or any of them be fit for the whole Pariſh to contribute to the amendment of; and in that caſe what reparations will be needful to be made, and what ſumme of money will be neceſſary to be raiſed for amending the ſame. And that the ſaid Scavengers do after ſuch view give publick notice (if the ſame have not been already done) to the Pariſhoners to meet for the making of an Aſſeſſement (if need require) by a pound rate upon all occupiers of Houſes, Lands, or other hereditaments according to the true yearly value thereof, and upon dead goods, commodities, or ſtock in Trade, of every Pariſhoner rated to the poor; rating twenty ſhillings goods to twenty pounds <hi>per Ann.</hi> land, ſo as all the rates together exceed not in one year <hi>12. d. per pound,</hi> according to the directions of the ſaid Ordinance. Which rate being ſo from time to time made and collected, is to be laid out for the publick charge of cleanſing and carrying away the ſoyl and filth, and for making the watercourſes and channels ſo that the current may free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly paſſe, and not to make any rate or disburſe any money for the reforming of defective pavements, but that the ſame are expected to be duly, and from time to time repaired by particular perſons, who according to the Law and cuſtom of this City are to repair the ſame upon pain of incurring ſuch fines and penalties as by Law are to be inflicted upon the offenders. And that the ſaid ſeverall Scavengers do take notice that at the time aforeſaid, or at ſome other convenient time before the next publick Seſſions to be kept for this City, they do not fail to ſummon the Inhabitants of their ſeverall Pariſhes to meet together, who according to the fourteenth Article of the ſaid Ordinance, are to make and ſet down ſuch Rules and Orders as the ſaid Pariſhoners ſo met ſhall think meet for the particulars aforementioned, or in any thing tending to the reformation of the premiſſes; which Orders together with the Rates aforementioned are to be by the reſpective Scavengers delivered to me in writing before the firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> next, to the intent the ſame may be preſented at the next publick Seſſions for the Peace to be holden for this City, that thereupon ſuch proceedings may be had as ſhall be juſt. And hereof fail you not.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Dated</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>the eight and twentieth day of June 1654.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Sadler.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>James Fleſher,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of LONDON.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
